<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>newsletter on Odin Programming Language</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/categories/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in newsletter on Odin Programming Language</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://odin-lang.org/categories/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>December 2022 Newsletter</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/news/newsletter-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/news/newsletter-2022-12/</guid><description>Release note highlights New map implementation is that high performance, cache-friendly, and uses a open-addressed Robin Hood hash map data structure with various optimizations for Odin Uses a smaller data structure than previously (4 pointers, down from 7) SOA-based memory layout Up to 4x-6x faster insertion and lookup on average Entries are store in non-contiguous cell-layout which means no element straddles across a cache line Only one allocation per map instead of two (previously hashes and entries) Allows for calling delete_key whilst iterating across the map And much more!</description></item><item><title>November 2022 Newsletter</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/news/newsletter-2022-11/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/news/newsletter-2022-11/</guid><description>Release note highlights raw_data was made an intrinsic, resulting in a speedup for slice heavy code. transmute can now be used on integer constants of the same internal endianness. Static_Arena and Growing_Arena have been unified into Arena, along with many other improvements to core:mem/virtual. Heavily improve time handling on Windows for time.now() and os.File_Info. And much more! Interview with Skytrias, author of Todool Q: Why don&amp;rsquo;t we begin with you telling us a bit about how you found out about Odin.</description></item></channel></rss>