<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on Odin Programming Language</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/docs/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on Odin Programming Language</description><language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://odin-lang.org/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Code Example</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/docs/code-example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 11:120:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/docs/code-example/</guid><description>The following code is from the demo.odin file which can be viewed and downloaded here:
https://github.com/odin-lang/Odin/blob/master/examples/demo/demo.odin
package main import &amp;quot;core:fmt&amp;quot; import &amp;quot;core:mem&amp;quot; import &amp;quot;core:os&amp;quot; import &amp;quot;core:thread&amp;quot; import &amp;quot;core:reflect&amp;quot; import &amp;quot;intrinsics&amp;quot; /* The Odin programming language is fast, concise, readable, pragmatic and open sourced. It is designed with the intent of replacing C with the following goals: * simplicity * high performance * built for modern systems * joy of programming # Installing Odin Getting Started - https://odin-lang.</description></item><item><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/docs/faq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 11:120:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/docs/faq/</guid><description>General What is the history of the project? The project started one evening in late July 2016 when Ginger Bill was annoyed with programming in C++. The language began as a Pascal clone (with begin and end and more) but changed quite quickly to become something else.
Bill originally tried to create a preprocessor for C to augment and add new capabilities to the language. However, he found this endeavour a dead-end.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/docs/install/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 11:120:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/docs/install/</guid><description>Odin is dead-simple to get started with!
Install using Homebrew brew install odin Clone or download Odin Clone the repository (recommended, git clone https://github.com/gingerBill/Odin) or download the latest release.
Note: Cloning the repository is recommended in order to make updating easier.
Download and include necessary extras Odin only supports x86-64 at the moment (64-bit) and it relies on LLVM (for code generation) and an external linker.
For Windows&amp;hellip; There&amp;rsquo;s a couple prerequisites here.</description></item><item><title>Odin Overview</title><link>https://odin-lang.org/docs/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 11:120:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://odin-lang.org/docs/overview/</guid><description>Introduction This article is a basic tutorial for the programming language Odin. This tutorial assumes a basic knowledge of programming concepts such as variables, statements, and types. It is recommend to read the Getting started with Odin guide.
Hellope! To begin this tour, let us start with a modified version of the famous &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; program:
package main import &amp;quot;core:fmt&amp;quot; main :: proc() { fmt.println(&amp;quot;Hellope!&amp;quot;); } Save this code to the file &amp;ldquo;hellope.</description></item></channel></rss>